# RAMESH ADHIKARI

Augusta, Georgia, USA | radhikari@augusta.edu

Website: ramesh-adhikari.github.io | GitHub:ramesh-adhikari | LinkedIn: adramesh

### PERSONAL PROFILE

A Ph.D. student at School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University. My research interests areas are in Distributed Algorithms, Blockchain Technology, and Computer Vision. I have 3.5 years of working experience in the field of information technology and services industry as a Software Engineer.

### **EDUCATION**

School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University

Ph.D. in Computer and Cyber Sciences

Pokhara University Kathmandu, Nepal 2018 - 2021

Masters of Science in Computer Engineering

Tribhuvan University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Kathmandu, Nepal

2013 - 2017

Augusta, Georgia

Aug 2022 - Present

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Adhikari, Ramesh, and Suresh Pokharel. Performance Evaluation of Convolutional Neural Network Using Synthetic Medical Data Augmentation Generated by GAN. International Journal of Image and Graphics (2021): 2350002

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant | Augusta University | Augusta, Georgia, USA Aug 2022 – Present Working on the distributed algorithm and blockchain technology, mainly on sharding in blockchain to solve the

Graduate Student | Nepal College of Information Technology | Kathmandu, Nepal 2020 - 2021Worked on machine learning and deep learning under faculty members' to complete master's research.

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Sanima Bank | Kathmandu, Nepal

scalability issue, under the supervision of Dr. Costas Busch.

May 2019 - Jun 2022

- Developed web applications for the banking process.
- Integrated API and web services.
- Developed Batch Script and SQL query to automate the process.

Software Engineer | SmartMobe Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Kathmandu, Nepal

Feb 2018 - April 2019

- Developed the API for mobile and web applications in collaboration with a team of 30 people by using relatable best practices and the latest technology and trends while keeping in mind the quality of code, scalability, and security.
- Researched new tools and technologies and made necessary changes or suggestions after weighing all alternatives. Continuously improve efficiency using new technologies and automation.

### ACHIEVEMENTS AND PARTICIPATION

- Attended International Symposium on Distributed Computing (DISC) conference, 2022, awarded by Augusta University, 2022.
- Star Performance Excellence Award, Sanima Bank Ltd, 2021.
- Full Scholarship for Master of Science in Computer Engineering from Pokhara University, 2018.

- Worked as a member of Kathford FOSS Community in Kathford Int'l college, monitored and guided the participants in EVOLVE() 2.0 software competition, 2017.
- First Runner Up, Software competition at Kantipur engineering college, 2015.

## **SKILLS**

Programming languages, Libraries, Tools: Python | Go | C | C++ | JavaScript | PHP | Tensorflow | MySQL | SQL server | Shell Scripting

**Broad Skills:** Distributed Algorithm | Distributed System | Blockchains | Algorithmic Analysis | Web Scraping | Database Design | Machine Learning | Cloud Computing | Problem Solving

### SELECTED PROJECTS

- Sharding in Blockchain [work in progress]
- Lockless transaction in Blockchain Sharding using multi-version concurrency control [work in progress]
- Implemented Blockchain Technology in the E-voting system
- Enhanced the performance of Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) by synthetically generating medical data using a generative adversarial network (GAN). [master's thesis]
- Designed microservice architecture and developed a workflow management system for Banking Industry.